[Mystic Nine]
[Adapted from the novel of Kennedy Xu]
[Episode 12]
[This story is purely fictional]
I gathered everyone today
to discuss something.
I'll cut to the chase.
The Otherworld Tower is under the military hospital.
I'm sure all of you are already aware of it.
I investigated it with Tiezui and Laogou.
We encountered many inexplicable events.
But most importantly,
we discovered
Japanese activities underneath.
Their leader is none other than Yoshiyuki Hatoyama.
On the surface, he is a merchant.
In reality,
he's a technical expert
from Japan.
He and his men
went underneath Changsha
in search of an item.
As for what it is,
we don't know yet.
But given his identity,
it must have something to do with the war.
So Master Zhang, you went down,
failed to capture the Japanese,
and allowed them to kidnap Laogou
right under your nose instead.
I was told
that when you guys descended,
Yoshiyuki Hatoyama was already dead.
But you performed some rituals
and resurrected him.
Is that right, Tiezui?
It's
really inexplicable.
You don't believe it, Master Zhang?
No.
It's all a trick.
We just haven't figured it out yet.
I don't believe in resurrection either.
However, I might have a plausible explanation.
Master Zhang, you said
you went down with Laogou and Tiezui.
You forgot someone.
I heard
that Miss Huo joined you too.
The Huo Clan is now just a shell of its former self.
It has no money
or manpower.
It can't survive in Mystic Nine anymore.
Master Zhang,
why did you bring the Huo Clan with you?
What's in it for you?
Not the Huo Clan.
Just Xiangu.
Isn't that odd?
Unless...
Unless you fancy Xiangu.
To revitalize the Huo Clan,
you lured Laogou underground
and killed him with her.
Then, you made up a story
of the resurrection of the Japanese
to fool us.
Once the whole thing is over,
you'll give Laogou's property to Xiangu.
Chen Pi, you're also a traitor.
Open your mouth again and I'll kill you.
Was I wrong though?
Your clan nominated you as the head
because you can make them money.
Listen.
Sleeping with Master Zhang
is a good deal.
Shut up, Chen Pi.
What are you on about?
Master Zhang didn't know Laogou went down.
I gave the order to Xiangu to descend.
Does anyone have any comments?
It was also my advice to Master Zhang.
Miss Huo
can hang upside down and descend into a salt mine.
She can be useful when the situation calls for it.
- She can be useful? Then I...
- Chen Pi.
Enough.
I don't care about Laogou's life anyway.
The
Otherworld Tower has collapsed,
and the Japanese are gone.
All we lost was a dog.
I know someone called Donkey.
Perhaps we can promote him.
Or, let's just do it now
and share Laogou's property.
The Mystic Nine will become the Mystic Eight.
Deal?
I'll get money? Sure.
30 years.
30 years ago,
when the Eight-Nation Alliance attacked Beiping,
the royalty was too busy fighting among themselves for power.
And now,
is any of them still alive?
The Japanese covet Northeastern China.
Dandong might fall anytime soon.
You think
Changsha will remain unscathed?
The Japanese
lie in wait in the tower for many years.
Laogou was kidnapped.
This is not a coincidence.
They wanted this to happen.
They must have a plan.
If we don't work together to fight back now,
when the Japanese
assemble their grenade launchers underneath this city,
do you think they have the patience to negotiate
the distribution of land with us?
Listen up.
None of us
will be spared, let alone the Mystic Nine.
Master Zhang.
What do you want us to do now?
Yoshiyuki Hatoyama
and Laogou are probably not in Changsha right now.
I have no jurisdiction to mobilize the soldiers outside the city.
I need your merchants,
informants,
and spies to find them for me.
Noted.
The Hong Clan will mobilize some men.
I think the Japanese merely
took Laogou hostage.
Impossible.
They planned carefully
to lure us down there for Laogou.
If their target is Laogou,
what about him
piques the Japanese's interest?
Laogou is good at taming animals.
He tames dogs and birds
to deliver messages.
But the Japanese did not take dogs
or birds with them.
[Map of the Otherworld Tower]
Perhaps they want
Laogou's talent for taming beasts.
What?
Are the Japanese assembling an army of dogs
or birds?
Laogou's dogs are fierce,
but they are not war-ready.
What do the Japanese want?
I see it now.
Laogou is a Japanese sympathizer.
He went down with you
to save the Japanese.
That's why he resurrected them.
Impossible.
I know how they left.
Master Zhang,
you said the tower was under the military hospital.
There is an underground stream.
[Waterway]
If they didn't leave through the front door,
the only alternative
is the underground stream.
[Liunian Hall A]
Third Master, you know the underground streams
of Changsha well.
I need to know how the Japanese left.
Please show us the way.
Sure.
For our future,
I shall come with you.
Thank you, everyone.
Xiangu.
Stay here.
I need your help for something.
Okay.
Do you want me to deal with Huo Wenhai?
No need, Master Zhang.
I know what I'm doing.
Having his attention
is not necessarily a bad thing.
Without a flaw,
we can't keep him contained.
I should be the one to hold his attention.
I can keep myself safe.
Be careful.
Worry not, Master Zhang.
Who told you to enter the Otherworld Tower?
Down there, we discovered
that someone had been dropping supplies for the Japanese.
It should be the same person who asked you
to enter the tower.
Who is it?
Ding Qiansui.
What did he ask you to do?
He wanted me to explore the place
and leave markings for him.
I suppose he wanted to enter the tower too.
However,
I found
many supplies for the Japanese down there.
I recognize some of them.
They were supplies Ding Qiansui
had asked my clan to purchase.
That was when I noticed
that he had been working with the Japanese.
And now, my clan is implicated.
You entered the ponds before we did.
What did you do?
I'm sick of being used.
So I need to find out the truth as soon as possible.
I want to know what the Japanese are up to,
and what Ding Qiansui
is plotting.
That way, I can act pre-emptively,
instead of being someone's pawn.
If you don't believe me, Master Zhang,
you can raid my clan,
or lock me up for interrogation.
I defended you just now
because I'm not sure if you're our enemy.
You went to the Otherworld Tower alone.
Once this becomes public,
I'll have to punish you
according to the military rules.
If this happens again,
I will show no mercy,
regardless of your excuse.
Go now.
I still need your help
regarding Laogou.
Spill it.
Master Zhang,
I might
have a lead.
After Laogou and you went into the ponds,
we found a photo among
the Japanese documents.
The photo
depicts a statue of the Otherworld Patriarch
woven with hair.
As you know,
not many people in this world
have voluminous hair.
Coincidentally,
I know of such a person.
At first, I thought it was just a pure coincidence.
But after I came out,
it continued to puzzle me.
Who is she?
She was a female customer who came to my father's stall
for a divination a long time ago.
She had really long hair.
But
I have never seen her since
and I don't know where she is now.
But don't worry, Master Zhang.
This
can be a lead.
I'll follow up with it.
Be quick.
Sure.
Now.
Sure, Master Zhang.
Goodbye.
Master,
so it was all Ding Qiansui's doing.
But isn't he a eunuch?
Why is he working with the Japanese?
Not just the Japanese.
He prospers in Changsha
because he has support
from the Americans.
Americans too?
His background is enigmatic.
He probably is working with the Japanese
and the Americans together.
Getting rid of him
won't be easy.
Xiaoyu, Xiaojin.
Yes.
Investigate Ding Qiansui.
I want
to eradicate him.
Yes.
Officer Huo, you're awake.
Where is the Mystic Nine?
Officer Huo, you have a misunderstanding.
You saw the Mystic Nine just now.
In a surge of emotion,
you passed out.
Don't take me for a fool.
You trespassed into military ground,
and attacked an officer.
By right, I can have all of you
executed.
Officer Huo.
The Mystic Nine heard that I was sick,
so they rushed here to check on me.
They didn't know you had imprisoned me.
Nonsense! My people are by the entrance.
They are not blind.
Wasn't Zhang Qishan here?
Bring him over.
I want to talk to him.
Master Zhang was here.
He saw that everyone barged in unlawfully
and lectured everyone.
He asked all of them to reflect upon themselves.
He too wanted to punish
the guards for their oversight.
But
since they are your soldiers,
he didn't want to go over your head.
So he asked me to tell you
to deal with them accordingly.
I have
delivered the message to you.
I feel unwell.
Allow me to rest first.
Officer Huo.
Do
relax yourself if you can.
It will be bad
if you fall sick in the future because of this.
You...
[Divination Service]
After we entered the Otherworld Tower,
we found a statue with hair
by the corner of the main passage.
The statue was around 170cm in height
and looked like a living person.
The hair used to make a statue
is quite rare.
Send the deceased off with no regrets.
For the living and the lives.
No more regrets, no more resentment.
A mystic once claimed
that the woman encountered the Otherworld Patriarch's sermon
and decided to join him.
Interestingly,
the followers were donned in ancient attire.
Their hair and accessories were not from the contemporary time.
They dressed as the Otherworld Patriarch did.
Further investigation
[Xishan]
alleged that the hair maiden
last appeared in a monastery in Xishan.
Our men went there many times
but due to geographical and manpower restraints,
we were unable to confirm where they went.
[Xishan]
This lead would be held off for now
until we obtained more resources.
This fate is doomed.
There is no escaping it.
[Alter Your Fate]
But if I risk my life for this lead,
I might just get us
a lifeline.
Sir.
Zhang Qishan allowed the Mystic Nine to trespass into Xie Residence
for
a meeting.
He has no respect for the military rules.
According to Bandits Punishment Regulations
and Section 32 of Army Punishment Regulations,
the Mystic Nine and Zhang Qishan...
Yes, I know.
[Yang Jian]
[Central China Disciplinary Commissioner]
The higher up will deal with it.
Sir,
Zhang Qishan is obviously working
with the Mystic Nine.
But the city defense requires Zhang Qishan.
If you're unhappy with the decision of the Ministry of War,
making a call won't do it.
Sir.
Huo Wenhai called again
to complain about Zhang Qishan.
[Luo Ang, Special Forces Director]
The Ministry of War
wants to get rid of gangsterism.
But the Mystic Nine
always gets extra leeway.
Is it because of Zhang Qishan?
I recruited him
personally back then.
He carried me
from the pile of dead bodies on the battlefield
and saved me.
My bond with Qishan
goes beyond a few sentences.
Are you going to spare the Mystic Nine?
There's no running away.
It's a national matter.
Time to settle the score.
Huo Wenhai is gone.
Of course, he left after a chat.
What brought you to my prison, Fourth Master?
I wouldn't want you to contact my rotten luck.
Fresh crabs from the Xiang River.
Each weighs ten liang.
I already gave some to the others in Mystic Nine.
It's tough to get to you
so I came in person.
You love crabs.
You'll be brokenhearted if you can't have them.
You had a wager with Li
when you joined the Mystic Nine.
I see you still remember it.
That's why you give us crabs every year.
You never once forget it.
Your integrity
sure is outstanding.
Of course.
People don't like me.
If I don't have a talent,
how can I survive in this world?
Once I make a promise,
no one can break it.
But that doesn't mean you should tell everyone
that I love crabs.
When you bring them every year, you'll say I love them.
Is it because my family name
is a homophone of crabs?
Whatever.
Just do whatever you want.
Isn't it boring to be stuck in here?
As you age,
you realize that being able to sit in peace
is also a kind of blessing.
I can find a way to get you out of here.
So long as you don't stay in Changsha.
Why don't you work for me?
It'll be more fun than where you are right now.
Clearing my name
is easy.
But as long as I'm part of the Mystic Nine,
I will still suffer the same fate.
Oh?
And I thought I was the only one in the Mystic Nine
to know that things would not end well for us.
The Mystic Nine exists
for a good reason.
But this reason
will not exist forever.
When the world is in turmoil,
society is in chaos.
Our leaders are busy fighting wars,
while the people can hardly fill their tummies.
Without the restraint of power,
an interim system of governance appeared
among the people.
The Mystic Nine
was born out of necessity.
We're not the good people,
but we give the poor a way to live.
Now that a new order has been established,
the foundation on which the Mystic Nine was built
has collapsed.
In this world,
grassroots organizations like the Mystic Nine
are not only redundant,
but also a threat to be uprooted.
Relics of the past will be gone eventually.
No point lamenting it.
Why not just protect yourself first?
I can kill Huo Wenhai for you.
As usual, 100 wen and we have a deal.
If my clan wants to come out unscathed,
it cannot do it alone.
The Mystic Nine is in the same boat.
If the higher-up doesn't want the Mystic Nine anymore,
they will get rid of us.
That's why they sent Huo Wenhai here.
He was part of the Mystic Nine.
He knows the Mystic Nine well.
If he wants to climb,
he needs to prove
that he has severed ties with the Mystic Nine.
He won't show mercy.
He will use everything he can
to get rid of the Mystic Nine.
Once the Ministry of War gets rid of the Mystic Nine,
it'll be a transformative event.
If one Huo Wenhai can't do it,
they'll send ten.
If not, a thousand
or ten thousand.
The Mystic Nine is destined to fall.
You and I can't escape from it.
Since you already know that,
why can't you let go of it?
Yes, I already know
that the Mystic Nine will fall.
But we
have a new variable now.
What is it?
Fifth Master.
Wu Laogou.
[Caopan Mountain]
You're awake.
Don't ask me where you are.
Just know that
you can't get out.
You came back to life.
Are you a human or a ghost?
No one can come back to life in this world.
But I saw it myself.
Guess then.
You have all the time in the world.
How did we pull that off?
Anyone else would have assumed
that it was a spell.
Yes.
That's what is so great
about the Chinese.
No, I mean your ancestors.
Not the modern Chinese.
During my first two years in the tower,
I too thought spells were real.
I was as shocked as you are.
But spells
don't exist in this world.
So you're saying what I've experienced
is just an illusion.
Not an illusion.
But not a spell either.
It's technology.
A wondrous technology.
Technology?
Yes.
Your ancestors several millennia ago
mastered this technology.
But the Chinese now
do not know it.
You think it's spells.
You scoundrel.
What are you on about?
You don't need to know.
Stand up, Fifth Master.
Come. Fifth Master.
Fifth Master.
I brought you here
to help me tame
a special animal.
I'll count on you.
Without it,
I can proceed with my next plan.
No, I refuse.
I have Unit 401 now.
The Unit 401 Zhang Qishan asked you
to find.
If you won't help me,
I'll kill them one by one.
When that happens,
your promise to Zhang Qishan
can never be delivered.
And your wish will never come true.
When a soldier steps on the battlefield,
he is prepared to sacrifice his life.
I'm a bandit,
but I share the same sentiment.
No.
I beg to differ.
In my research,
soldiers and bandits are not the same thing.
Piss a bandit off
and they might kill your emperor.
Fifth Master,
let me share a story with you.
It'll answer your questions.
Four years ago, I entered the Otherworld Tower in Changsha
to find out the secret of Yin Changsheng.
I was stuck underground
for three years.
Until the first parasite
[Torii Totori, Hatoyama's Superior]
among you appeared.
Things finally took a turn for the better.
I thought with enough money,
this problem would be solved.
After all, humans are greedy.
To my dismay,
after spending so much time,
they only found Ding Qiansui.
He took his time
to leverage the Huo Clan.
But by then, we almost
starved to death.
We almost gave up.
Ding Qiansui took our funds
and bought the Huo Clan.
If your clan wants to remain in the Mystic Nine,
you'll need help.
I have the money
and the connections.
But you'll need to help me out too.
We can help you,
but you'd better keep your promise.
The Huo Clan has its own acquisition channel
that evades even Zhang Qishan's supervision.
So,
they kept providing supplies to us
without anyone knowing.
As I explored the tower,
I found a crack on the mountain.
It leads to the world outside.
It's too small for a human to squeeze through,
but it's big enough for other things.
For example, Ding Qiansui can drop us supplies.
Come.
Keep up.
Put it here.
Yes.
With food,
our living conditions underground stabilized.
I knew I couldn't leave the tower this soon,
so I focused on the secrets of the tower.
First, I studied all three of Yin Changsheng's spells.
Then,
I figured out the science behind the making of those monsters.
Most importantly,
I found a pill.
Once taken, it makes your body mutate.
I tested it on my subordinate.
And finally, we have a man
who can climb the cliff
to leave the Otherworld Tower.
Ding Qiansui, these are the pills.
I was stuck in the tower for three years.
In these three years,
I figured out
almost all the secrets in this tower.
The Otherworld Tower
is but a carefully designed
scheme.
As my research continued,
I discovered that the Otherworld Tower
was just an entrance
to a more mystical place.
Is this a place accessible only
through the underground streams?
As expected of the Fifth Master.
You're smart.
Yes.
We travelled several hundred kilometers
on the underground stream
until we reached a hidden exit that leads
to this place.
But this place isn't the destination
of our trip.
To reach the destination,
we need your help.
So, I had no choice
but to kidnap you.
But I couldn't do it in Changsha.
That'd be too risky.
Therefore,
you lured me to you.
That's right.
I had Ding Qiansui make an old stone tablet.
Then, I bought several men on Unit 401
so that they could tell the rest to dig it.
They would spread rumors
to compel the rest to join them.
The pills had already been ground
and mixed with the soil.
When they dug,
mud would get on them.
They would be poisoned
and become docile.
Then, I had my men
lead them to the Otherworld Tower
to lure Zhang Qishan.
And finally,
you came.
Why didn't you ask your men
to kidnap me right away?
You think I've never tried that?
[Wu's Residence]
I know Zhang Qishan's and your capabilities very well.
Once the Otherworld Tower became public,
we only had one shot.
So, I took a gamble.
Why did you
let me perform those three spells?
Don't pin that on me.
I did not ask you to perform those three spells.
It was all in your head.
Oh, humans
and their imagination.
Be it spells
or whatever wonderful thing
in this world,
they are all your imagination.
So, I misjudged the situation.
You did not force me to carry out the spells.
It was all in my head.
What is wrong with you?
Are you sure there were three spells?
Are you sure you made a judgment?
Are you sure there even are spells?
What do you mean?
Explain now.
The confusion you feel now
is the effect of the secret.
It is that secret
that makes the spells in the tower
look so realistic.
It makes everyone believe
that the Otherworld Patriarch used it to establish a cult,
that Yin Changsheng was a real immortal.
Their followers believed vehemently in their powers.
You are a follower too.
We, the Japanese, are always honest.
Allow me
to tell you everything.
A toast to me?
Of course.
Feel free to think of this
as a victory lap.
After all, my plan
took three years to come to fruition.
I studied you for three years.
Fifth Master,
I've been waiting
for this moment.
Oh.
The Huo Clan played a part in everything.
Huo Xiangu isn't aware of it.
But as the head of the clan,
if people find out that her clan is working with the Japanese,
she will be held accountable.
If you refuse to help me,
she won't die in our hands.
She will die in the hands of the Ministry of War's Spy Execution Squad.
I know you still want to escape.
But at this point,
you might as well tame that creature for me
while you find an opportunity to escape.
Anyway.
Mr. Wu.
Let's start tomorrow.
I'll count on you.
[Li's Residence]
My son, say "Father."
Say "Father" and you'll have good food tonight.
Say "Father."
What is going on?
Take him away and play with him.
- Go play. - Go.
- Come. - Go.
- Go play now. - Go.
How many times have I told you?
Don't teach him the wrong thing.
[Fu Chunhua, Sister-in-law]
People will talk.
So what?
My brother passed away many years ago.
Your son is already this big,
but you still refuse to move into this yard.
What if people talk behind your back?
I'm not afraid of that.
I'm a woman.
I hardly venture out.
What's there to be afraid of?
But you're different.
You're Third Master of the Mystic Nine.
And?
I'm just an ordinary man.
I have survived
worse.
If you hadn't protected me back then,
I would have died in the ditch.
Chunhua, what is bothering you?
If you don't like my dirty deeds,
I can just retire now.
Aren't you supposed to work with Master Zhang?
Pack up now.
See you.
San'er.
Third Master.
Come here.
- Chunhua is... - Third Master.
Don't you have a trip with Master Zhang?
Let me pack your things.
[Files]
Impossible.
No records on Ding Qiansui?
He prospers in Changsha
because he has support
from the Americans.
Bring Third Master over.
Yes!
Master.
Third Master is here.
He wants to see you by the entrance.
[Changsha Defense Headquarters]
Third Master.
You're here, Master Zhang.
Where are your men?
On standby.
That's all you're bringing?
A few elite soldiers will do.
I brought 300 men.
That's a lot.
It sure seems like it.
What about this?
Let's not bring anyone.
For our peace.
We're looking for an underground stream.
So why are we going up to a mountain?
Master Zhang, you are good at the arts of war.
But you don't know geography well.
The underground stream is an ancient waterway.
The mountain layout has already changed,
but there is an opening at the foot of the mountain.
We can enter through it.
How long will it take?
Two to three days.
I'm tired.
Let's rest here.
Will you push me off, Master Zhang?
No.
Oh?
Everyone in the Mystic Nine has done it,
except you.
Tiezui too?
I looked at him in his eyes.
He certainly thought about it.
But unfortunately,
his hands were too shaky.
You're enjoying it, Third Master.
No?
I think my killer
isn't born yet.
The higher you climb,
the harder you fall.
But think about it.
If you don't climb this high,
you won't get
a view this great.
Don't you agree?
Given your financial prowess,
have you thought about retiring
and living some peaceful days?
The men behind me
count on me to feed their tummies.
And then,
there are many more who want me dead.
So if I
retire,
I won't even have to do much
to meet my maker.
Master Zhang,
if you were me,
would you retire?
See?
Don't think too far ahead.
There's no point.
The Japanese made a mess.
Let's just figure out how to deal with them.
I bet the Japanese would never see this coming,
that one day,
a cripple like me would be the one
to stop them.
Don't sell yourself short, Third Master.
You've always
been the purest among us in the Mystic Nine.
The rest has changed more or less.
I hope you can always
stay true to yourself.
♪The past fades like smoke♪
♪A choice is made in silence♪
♪In this labyrinthine puzzle♪
♪Who can reach the shore?♪
♪Just an ordinary farewell♪
♪The sun seems to shine bright over our heads♪
♪But this could be our last trip together♪
♪The spring breeze continues outside♪
♪Who was it who left in such haste?♪
♪Caught in the game, the raging waves fall silent♪
♪Who believes in fate?♪
♪For my home and my country, the years pass like a dream♪
♪When the song ends, who will still be waiting?♪
♪With a nod, we bid farewell and set out again♪
♪Take care♪
♪We once raced♪
♪For the dawn♪
♪Ever-lasting bond, a satisfying vindication♪
♪In the web of fate♪
♪No one can escape♪
♪Life and death cut like a blade♪
♪We too were young once♪
♪Fortunate to brave the raging waves together♪
♪Keep the ember lit♪
♪To illuminate the journey ahead♪
♪The spring breeze continues outside♪
♪Who was it who left in such haste?♪
♪Caught in the game, the raging waves fall silent♪
♪Who believes in fate?♪
♪For my home and my country, the years pass like a dream♪
♪When the song ends, who will still be waiting?♪
♪With a nod, we bid farewell and set out again♪
♪Please, do take care of yourself♪